Howard W. and Jean Lipman
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Research and Writings Files, 1925-1997, undated, Series 4:; (Boxes 18-28, 48, OV 50, 53; 10.3 linear ft.)
  - Other Writings and Research Projects, 1932-1994, undated, 4.5:
    - "Save Our Planet" Project, Artist Material (See also, Calder, Oversized Miscellaneous Material, "Save Our Planet" Poster Sketch, Box 50), 1970-1971 (Box 28)
    - "Save Our Planet" Project, Miscellaneous Material, 1970-1972, undated (Box 28)
    - Alexander Calder, Miscellaneous Oversized Materials, 1970-1974, undated (Box 50 (OV))
- Art in America Editorial Files, 1932-1972, undated, Series 5:; (Boxes 28-45, 49, OV 50; 17.3 linear ft.)
  This series chronicles the editorial activities of Jean Lipman from the magazine's early years until Lipman's resignation in 1970. Materials found in the series include correspondence; copyright applications for issues; advertising and publicity lists, promotional materials and contracts; award announcements; photographs and negatives; occasional drafts of articles and feature columns; proofs; ledger books and invoices from early years of the magazine when Lipman briefly owned it; and notes and miscellaneous printed matter related to the production of the various magazine issues. Arrangement of the series is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year.
  A sampling of correspondents that can be found in the general correspondence files of this series include: Milton Avery, Marcel Breuer, Rupert Conrad, Frances Parkinson Keyes, Eliot Noyes, Eleanor Roosevelt, and James Thurber.
  - Advertising and Publicity (Box 28)
    - Advertiser Lists, 1955-1956, undated (Box 28)
    - Contracts, 1953-1955, undated (Box 28)
    - Exchange and Paid Ads, 1953-1970, undated, (3 folders) (Box 28)
    - Ideas for Increasing Circulation and Promotion, 1957-1961, undated (Box 28)
    - Press Releases and Announcements, 1967-1970, undated (Box 28)
    - Solicitations for Magazine Submissions,1938-1939 (Box 28)
  - Art in America Annual Award, 1958-1962, undated (Box 28)
  - Art in America Society, 1959-1961, undated (Box 28)
  - Awards, 1966-1968 (Box 28)
  - Contracts, 1951-1962 (Box 28)
  - Copyrights, 1952-1957 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 28)
    - June 1932-December 1938 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 29)
    - January-December 1939 (Box 29)
    - January-December 1940 (Box 29)
    - January-December 1941, (5 folders) (Box 29)
    - January-December 1942, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - January-December 1943, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - January-December 1944, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - circa 1943-1944 (Box 29)
    - January-December 1945, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - January-December 1946, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - January-March 1947 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 30)
    - April-December 1947, (3 folders) (Box 30)
    - January-December 1949, (3 folders) (Box 30)
    - January-December 1950 (Box 30)
    - January-December 1951, (5 folders) (Box 30)
    - January-December 1952, (4 folders) (Box 30)
    - January-September 1953, (6 folders) (Box 30)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 31)
    - October-December 1953, (5 folders) (Box 31)
    - January-October 1954, (18 folders) (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 32)
    - November-December 1954, (3 folders) (Box 32)
    - January-December 1955, (17 folders) (Box 32)
    - circa 1955 (Box 32)
    - January-March 1956, (3 folders) (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 33)
    - April-December 1956, (9 folders) (Box 33)
    - circa 1956 (Box 33)
    - January-December 1957, (11 folders) (Box 33)
    - January-December 1958, (12 folders) (Box 33)
    - January-August 1959, (8 folders) (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 34)
    - September-December 1959, (4 folders) (Box 34)
    - circa 1959 (Box 34)
    - January-December 1960, (12 folders) (Box 34)
    - circa 1960 (Box 34)
    - January-December 1961, (12 folders) (Box 34)
    - January-December 1962, (12 folders) (Box 34)
    - circa 1962 (Box 34)
    - January-March 1963, (3 folders) (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 35)
    - April-December 1963, (9 folders) (Box 35)
    - circa 1963 (Box 35)
    - January-December 1964, (12 folders) (Box 35)
    - circa 1964 (Box 35)
    - January-December 1965, (12 folders) (Box 35)
    - circa 1965 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 36)
    - January-December 1966, (12 folders) (Box 36)
    - circa 1966 (Box 36)
    - January-December 1967, (12 folders) (Box 36)
    - circa 1967 (Box 36)
    - January-December 1968, (12 folders) (Box 36)
    - January-December 1969, (12 folders) (Box 36)
    - circa 1969 (Box 36)
    - January-November 1970, (11 folders) (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, General (Box 37)
    - circa 1970 (Box 37)
    - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 37)
  - Editorial Material (Box 37)
    - 1953, Winter Issue, 1953 (Box 37)
    - 1954, May Issue, 1954, undated (Box 37)
    - 1954, October Issue, 1954, undated (Box 37)
    - 1954, December Issue, 1954, undated (Box 37)
    - 1954, Winter Issue ("Americans with a Future"), 1953-1954, undated (Box 37)
    - 1955, Feb. Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1954-1955, undated (Box 37)
    - 1955, May Issue ("Restoration Villages"), 1954-1955, undated (Box 37)
    - 1955, October Issue, 1955, undated, (2 folders) (Box 37)
    - 1955, December Issue, 1955, undated (Box 37)
    - 1956, February Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1955-1956, undated, (3 folders) (Box 37)
    - 1956, Spring Issue ("Art in Industry"), 1943-1956, undated, (6 folders) (Box 37)
  - Editorial Material (Box 38)
    - 1956, Spring Issue ("Art in Industry"), 1943-1956, undated, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1956, Fall Issue, 1956, undated (Box 38)
    - 1956, December Issue, 1956, undated (Box 38)
    - 1957, February Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1956-1957, undated, (4 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1957, Spring-Summer Issue, 1953-1957, undated, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1957, Fall Issue, 1957, undated, (3 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1957, Winter Issue, 1957, undated, (4 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1958, March Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1956-1959, undated, (2 folders) (Box 38)
  - Editorial Material (Box 39)
    - 1958, March Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1956-1959, undated, (3 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1958, Summer Issue, 1956-1958 (Box 39)
    - 1958, Fall Issue, 1948-1958, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1958, Winter Issue, 1958 (Box 39)
    - 1959, Spring Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A.), 1958-1959 (Box 39)
    - 1959, Summer Issue, circa 1959 (Box 39)
    - 1959, Winter Issue, 1958-1959, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1960, Spring Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1958-1960, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1960, Summer Issue ("International Look at the U.S.A."), 1959-1960, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1960, Fall Issue, 1959-1960, undated, (2 folders) (Box 39)
  - Editorial Material (Box 40)
    - 1960, Winter Issue, 1957-1960, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1961, Spring Issue ("New Talent in the U.S.A.") 1960-1961, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1961, Summer Issue, 1958-1961, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1961, Fall Issue, 1961, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1961, Winter Issue, 1960-1961, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1962, Issue No. 1 ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1961, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1962, Issue No. 2, 1961-1962 (Box 40)
    - 1962, Issue No. 3, 1961-1962, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1964, Issue No. 4, 1962, undated (Box 40)
    - 1963, Issue No. 1 (50th Anniversary of magazine), 1962-1963, (3 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1963, Issue No. 2 ("Art for Everyday Living"), 1962-1963, (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Editorial Material (Box 41)
    - 1963, Issue No. 3, 1962-1963, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1963, Issue No. 4, 1962-1963, (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1963, Issue No. 5, 1962-1963, undated (Box 41)
    - 1963, Issue No. 6, 1962-1963, undated (Box 41)
    - 1964, Issue No. 1, 1962-1963 (Box 41)
    - 1964, Issue No. 2, 1962-1963 (Box 41)
    - 1964, Issue No. 3, 1962-1964, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1964, Issue No. 4, 1963-1964 (Box 41)
    - 1964, Issue No. 5, 1963-1964, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1964, Issue No. 6, 1964, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1965, Issue No. 1, 1963-1964, (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1965, Issue No. 2, 1963-1965, (2 folders) (Box 41)
  - Editorial Material (Box 42)
    - 1965, Issue No. 3, 1964-1965 (Box 42)
    - 1965, Issue No. 4, 1964-1965 (Box 42)
    - 1965, Issue No. 5, 1960-1965, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1965-1966, Issue No. 6, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1966, Issue No. 1, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1966, Issue No. 2, 1964-1966 (Box 42)
    - 1966, Issue No. 3, 1965-1966 (Box 42)
    - 1966, Issue No. 4 ("New Talent in the U.S.A."), 1964-1966, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1966, Issue No. 5, 1965-1966, (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1966, Issue No. 6, 1964-1966 (Box 42)
    - 1967, Issue No. 1, 1966-1967 (Box 42)
    - 1967, Issue No. 2, 1966-1967 (Box 42)
    - 1967, Issue No. 3, 1965-1967 (Box 42)
    - 1967, Issue No. 4, 1967 (Box 42)
    - 1967, Issue No. 5, 1965-1967 (Box 42)
    - 1967, Issue No. 6, 1967 (Box 42)
    - 1968, Issue No. 1, 1965-1967 (Box 42)
    - 1968, Issue No. 2, 1967-1968 (Box 42)
  - Editorial Material (Box 43)
    - 1968, Issue No. 3, 1967-1968 (Box 43)
    - 1968, Issue No. 4, 1967-1968 (Box 43)
    - 1968, Issue No. 5, 1967-1968 (Box 43)
    - 1968, Issue No. 6, 1968 (Box 43)
    - 1969, Issue No. 2, 1968-1969 (Box 43)
    - 1969, Issue No. 3, 1968-1969 (Box 43)
    - 1969, Issue No. 4, 1969 (Box 43)
    - 1969, Issue No. 5, 1969 (Box 43)
    - 1969, Issue No. 6, 1968-1969 (Box 43)
    - 1970, Issue No. 1, 1969-71 (Box 43)
    - 1970, Issue No. 2, 1966-1969 (Box 43)
    - 1970, Issue No. 3, 1970 (Box 43)
    - 1970, Issue No. 4, 1966-1970 (Box 43)
    - 1970, Issue No. 5, 1969-1970 (Box 43)
    - 1970, Issue No. 6, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1971, Issue No. 1, 1971 (Box 43)
    - 1971, Issue No. 2 (Cancelled Issue), 1968-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Cartoons and Drawings (See also Calder, Oversized Miscellaneous Material, "Art in America" Cover Sketch, Box 50) 1961-1963, undated (Box 43)
    - Ideas for Future Issues, circa 1955, undated (Box 43)
    - Manuscripts Drafts from Unidentified Issues, 1942-1962, undated (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1952-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous Unidentified Material, 1930-1970, undated (Box 43)
    - Photographs from Unidentified Issues, circa 1948-1963, undated (Box 43)
    - "Signs and Symbols of the U.S.A.," 1963-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Style and Copy Fitting Sheets, 1945, undated (Box 43)
  - Editorial Meetings, 1955-1969, (3 folders) (Box 44)
  - Financial Material (Box 44)
    - Advertising Commissions, 1955-1957 (Box 44)
    - Bank Statements, 1953-1957 (Box 44)
    - Cash Journal, 1940-1953 (Box 44)
    - Check Registers, 1945-1957, (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - Debit and Credit Ledger, 1941-1953, (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - General Ledger (See also Box 48), 1941-1953 (Box 44)
    - Invoices, 1940-1957, (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - Stock Subscription, 1960 (Box 44)
    - Subscription and Advertising Journal, 1953-1955 (Box 44)
    - Subscription and Advertising Journal, 1955 (Box 44)
  - Lists of Contributors and Subscribers, 1940-1941, undated (Box 44)
  - Notes and Miscellaneous Material, 1883, 1941-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Permissions and Reprints, 1954-1970, undated, (4 folders) (Box 45)
  - Resignation of Lipman as Editor, 1969-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Schedules for Publications, 1966-1969, undated (Box 45)
  - Search for Publisher, 1956, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Sherman, Frederick Fairchild, 1934-1943, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - Special Projects (Box 45)
    - Books, 1955-1970, undated, (4 folders) (Box 45)
    - Exhibitions, 1956-1970, undated (Box 45)
    - Miscellaneous Products, 1970, undated (Box 45)
    - Portfolios, 1955-1964, undated (Box 45)
    - "Save Our Planet" Posters (See Calder, Oversized Miscellaneous Material, Box 50) 1970-1974, undated (Box 45)
    - Stamp Design Project, 1962-1963 (Box 45)
  - Vision, Inc., 1957-1968, undated (Box 45)
  - Wittenborn and Company, 1956-1957 (Box 45)
  - Art in America Editorial Files, Oversized Financial Material: General Ledger, 1941-1953 (Box 49 (Sol))
  - Calder, Oversized Miscellaneous Material, 1970-1974, undated (Box 50 (OV))